Chetan Acharekar

Mumbai | +918080902603 | <u>acharekarchetan4@gmail.com</u> | https://www.linkedin.com/in/chetanacharekar/ | https://chetan-acharekar.github.io/ |

Summary

Passionate software engineer with **7+ years of full stack development experience** with focus on backend development. Seeking to take next career step in a respected organization with dedication to world class quality. Keen Interest in microservices and distributed systems, systems operating at scale. Also, I aspire to have distinguished career in machine learning.

Skills

- Primary Java, Nodejs
- Secondary Redis, Python, SQL. Linux, Docker
- Novice AI, CNN

- AWS(ECS/S3/lambda/route53), GIT, Jenkins
- Interests: Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Microservices, Distributed system design, Pandas, Keras

Experience

HERE technologies - Senior Software Engineer

2020 to Current

- Creating and maintaining micro service for automation of manual map edit tasks
- Working on POC to use NLP and CNN for profanity detection

BSG LTD - Senior Software engineer

2017 to 2020

- Enhanced month end and year end applications to run few seconds, which were taking hours to complete
- Created many services for Core Banking Application [Cashier's module/Locker/account operations]
- Fixed issues in Cash Transaction with better system [maintaining track of each penny that enters or leaves system]

CitiusTech - Software Engineer

2014 to 2016

- Created end to end iot module working on mqtt protocol for remote patient monitoring including hybrid mobile app, iWatch integration for heartbeat scanning, backend to receive real time data.
- Wrote terraform scripts to deploy various AWS services. Started as POC and later converted it to working project, which all team members can use

Others

- Created NPM package: native-requestify. Medium blog link
- Developed and maintained https://fightvscorona.in/ to help India fight corona
- Completed deeplearning.ai Neural Networks and Deep Learning course
- Trekking blogging site to promote trekking in Sahyadri region. Desktop site /Mobile
- · Created chatbot for bookmyshow using API.Al services, which was live on Facebook

Education and Training

Btech Electronics HSC SSC VJTI, Mumbai Kelkar College SVVM Pointer: 7.9 Score:88.33% Score:93.07%

2010 - 2014 2008- 2010 2000 - 2008